Jennings Lumber Co. mss., 1867-1915 LMC 1643
Lilly Library
Jennings Lumber Co. mss.
1867-1915
Lilly Library
Jennings, Levi Allen, 1834-1914
Jennings, Simon Peter, 1840-1914
Jennings, Harry Edmond, 1874-
Jennings, Charles Wesley, 1876-
LMC 1643
11 Boxes 10 standard, 1 custom
The Jennings Lumber Co. mss., 1867-1915, consists of the accounts, records, and correspondence of the Jennings family of New Castle, Indiana, with particular reference to their several business and manufacturing firms.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1986
Biographical Note
Levi Allen Jennings, 1834-1914, was born in Wayne County, Ohio, the first child of Obadiah and Mary Jennings. After schooling and some years as principal agent for the Ball Reaper and Mower Company, Jennings decided to leave Ohio, and settled in New Castle, Indiana in 1867. His parents joined him that same year and he and his father entered into a saw mill business, and somewhat into the general lumber trade. The following year Jennings opened a planing mill, lumber yard, and a sash, blind, and door factory. Within a short time he became primarily engaged in the manufacture of furniture.
Levi's brother, Simon Peter Jennings, 1840-1914, joined Levi in New Castle in 1868, and with Levi and another partner, opened a general hardware and stove trade. In 1875, Simon entered the lumber and building-material trade and in 1889 enlarged his factory to allow the manufacture of axe, hammer, pick, and sledge handles.
Simon's eldest son, Harry Edmond Jennings, 1874-, took part in his father's business from his childhood days. In 1893, Harry established his own factory for the manufacture of barrel hoops. He opened a plant for the manufacture of staves in Milton, Indiana, in 1904 in partnership with his youngest brother, Walter Pickering Jennings, 1878-. Walter re-settled in Milton to manage the business directly.
Simon's second son, Charles Wesley Jennings, 1876-, also entered the business and in 1898 went to Charleston, West Virginia to operate a branch of the handle business. He returned to New Castle in 1900 and continued working with his father in all facets of the enterprise.
The Jennings lumber yard and building supply outlet prospered on the same site from 1885-1975. In 1975 the building and its contents were sold at auction.
Scope and Content Note
The papers present here include: incoming correspondence, 1891-1902, virtually all of which is business related and primarily for Simon P. Jennings; twelve copy books of outgoing correspondence, November 1890-October 1904; thirty-three "Lumber Order" books, March 1885-October 1906; three "Timber" books, 1890-1900; three "Broom" order books and production records, November 1900-May 1902; fourteen "Handle" order and shipping books, 1889-1902, and three payroll books, 1893-1898; order, production, and shipping books for "Hoops," April 1894-November 1897; and six volumes of "Accounts payable," 1890-1911.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Correspondence, II. Lumber Order Books, III. Timber Books, IV. Bank Books, V. Payroll Books, VI. Duplicate Bills of Lading (carbon copies), VII. Order Books, VIII. Shipping Books, IX. Correspondence Copy Books, X. Accounts Payable, XI. Order Books, XII. Miscellaneous
Furniture industry and trade; Lumber trade
- I. Correspondence
  - 1891-1892 (Box 1)
  - 1893 (Box 1)
  - 1894 (Box 1)
  - 1895, Jan.-June (Box 1)
  - 1895, July-Dec. (Box 2)
  - 1896 (Box 2)
  - 1897 (Box 2)
  - 1898-1902 (Box 2)
- II. Lumber Order Books
  - #1a, 1885, Mar. 17-1886, June 14 (Box 3)
  - #2a, 1886, June 18-1887, Aug. 27 (Box 3)
  - #1, 1888, Mar. 1-1888, June 23 (Box 3)
  - #2, 1888, Sept. 13-1889, Apr. 18 (Box 3)
  - #3, 1889, Apr. 22-1889, Sept. 21 (Box 3)
  - #4, 1889, Sept. 21-1890, Apr. 11 (Box 3)
  - #5, 1890, Apr. 14-1890, Sept. 23 (Box 3)
  - #6, 1890, Sept. 24-1891, May 29 (Box 3)
  - #7, 1891, May 28-1891, Nov. 10 (Box 3)
  - #8, 1891, Nov. 11-1892, May 27 (Box 3)
  - #9, 1892, May 28-1892, Sept. 15 (Box 3)
  - #11, 1893, Mar. 14-1893, July 20 (Box 3)
  - #12, 1893, July 21-1894, Feb. 13 (Box 3)
  - #13, 1894, Feb. 15-1894, July 24 (Box 3)
  - #14, 1894, July 24-1894, Dec. 29 (Box 3)
  - #15, 1895, Jan. 1-1895, July 27 (Box 3)
  - #16, 1895, July 27-1895, Dec. 21 (Box 3)
  - #17, 1895, Dec. 23-1896, Aug. 12 (Box 3)
  - #18, 1896, Aug. 14-1897, May 5 (Box 3)
  - #20, 1898, May 10-1899, June 3 (Box 4)
  - #21, 1899, June 5-1900, Sept. 17 (Box 4)
  - #22, 1900, Sept. 18-1901, Oct. 3 (Box 4)
  - #23, 1901, Oct. 7-1902, Mar. 25 (Box 4)
  - #25, 1899, Mar.-1903, May 5 (Box 4)
  - #26, 1903, May 1-1903, Sept. 30 (Box 4)
  - #28, 1904, June 4-1904, Dec. 12 (Box 4)
  - #29, 1904, Dec. 12-1905, July 28 (Box 4)
  - #31, 1906, Mar. 1-1906, Oct. 30 (Box 4)
- III. Timber Books
  - 1890, Dec. 24-1894, Oct. 19 (Box 4)
  - 1894, Oct. 23-1896, Oct. 23 (Box 4)
  - 1896, Oct. 23-1900, Mar. 7 (Box 4)
- IV. Bank Books
  - S.P. Jennings, 1891, Feb.-1892, Mar. (Box 5)
  - Newcastle Hoop Co., 1894, Jan.-1896, Apr. (Box 5)
  - S.P. Jennings, 1894, Apr.-1895, Oct. (Box 5)
  - S.P. Jennings, 1895, Nov.-1897, Mar. (Box 5)
  - S.P. Jennings, 1897, Mar.-1898, Oct. (Box 5)
- V. Payroll Books
  - 1893, Dec.-1894, Sept. (Box 5)
  - 1894, Oct.-1895, July (Box 5)
  - 1897, Apr.-1898, Feb. (Box 5)
- VI. Duplicate Bills of Lading (carbon copies)
  - 1897, Jan. 13-Mar. 8 (Box 5)
  - 1897, Mar. 10-Apr. 23 (Box 5)
  - 1897, June 7-July 21 (Box 5)
  - 1897, Aug.3-Sept. 14 (Box 5)
  - 1897, Nov. 27-1898, Jan 22 (Box 5)
  - 1898, Jan. 22-Mar. 17 (Box 5)
  - 1898, May 17-July 15 (Box 5)
  - 1898, Nov. 7-1899, June 26 (Box 5)
  - 1900, Sept. 6-Nov. 20 (Box 5)
  - 1901, May 25-Aug. 5 (Box 5)
  - 1901, Oct. 28-1902, Feb. 15 (Box 5)
- VII. Order Books
  - #1, 1888, May 22-1889, Nov. 29 (Box 6)
  - #2, 1889, Dec. 2-1890, Sept. 6 (Box 6)
  - #3, 1890, Sept. 9-1891, Apr. 1 (Box 6)
  - #4, 1891, Apr. 6-1891, Dec. 5 (Box 6)
  - #5, 1891, Dec. 7-1892, July 15 (Box 6)
  - #6, 1892, July 19-1893, Feb. 6 (Box 6)
  - #7, 1893, Apr. 15-1894, Feb. 2 (Box 6)
  - #8, 1894, Feb. 3-1894, Sept. 29 (Box 6)
  - #9, 1894, Sept. 27-1895, Nov. 20 (Box 6)
  - #10, 1895, Nov. 20-1897, July 6 (Box 6)
- VIII. Shipping Books
  - #1, 1894, Oct. 1-1895, Sept. 20 (Box 6)
  - #2, 1895, Sept. 20-1896, Dec. 11 (Box 6)
  - #3, 1896, Dec. 12-1898, Feb. 10 (Box 6)
  - #4, 1898, Feb. 10-1902, Dec. 3 (Box 6)
- IX. Correspondence Copy Books
  - #1, 1890, Nov. 7-1891, Oct. 24 (Box 7)
  - #2, 1891, Oct. 27-1892, Dec. 7 (Box 7)
  - #3, 1893, Nov. 29-1895, Oct. 26 (Box 7)
  - #4, 1895, Oct. 24-1897, Jan. 28 (Box 7)
  - #5, 1897, Jan. 30-1897, Dec. 31 (Box 7)
  - #6, 1898, Jan. 1-1899, Apr. 25 (Box 7)
  - #7, 1900, Feb. 10-1901, Dec. 26 (Box 7)
  - #8, 1901, Dec. 30-1905, June 2 (Box 8)
  - #9, 1901, June 18-1902, June 5 (Box 8)
  - #10, 1902, June 18-1903, Sept. 16 (Box 8)
  - #11, 1902, Aug. 23-1903, Dec. 7 (Box 8)
  - #12, 1903, Nov. 7-1904, Oct. 25 (Box 8)
- X. Accounts Payable
  - #1, 1890 (Box 8)
  - #2, 1891 (Box 8)
  - #3, 1894 (Box 8)
  - #4, 1894-1896 (Box 8)
  - #5, 1901-1903 (Box 8)
  - #6, 1911 (Box 8)
- XI. Order Books
  - 1892, Oct. 3-1894, Feb. (Box 9)
  - 1894, Feb. 10-1895, July 6 (Box 9)
  - 1898, July 12-1901, Jan. 19 (Box 9)
  - 1901, Jan. 15-1902, July 3 (Box 9)
  - 1902, July 5-1903, July 6 (Box 9)
  - #1, 1894, Apr. 17-1895, Nov. 6 (Box 10)
  - #2, 1895, Nov. 6-1897, Nov. 20 (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous
  - Brooms (Box 5)
  - Order Book, Nov.5-1902, May 31 (Box 5)
  - Production records, 1901, Jan.-1902, Jan. (Box 5)
  - Purchasing time study, 1900, Mar.-1901 (Box 5)
  - Handles (Box 5)
  - Handles (Box 6)
  - Cancelled checks (Box 6)
  - Financial Records (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Accounts receivable, undated (Box 9)
  - Invoice record, 1907, Dec.-1915, Dec. (Box 10)
  - Record of assessments, collections and abatements: Internal revenue, 1867-1890 (Box 10)
  - Hoops (Box 10)
  - Production, 1894, Oct. 4-1897, Nov. 13 (Box 10)
  - Shipping, 1896, Dec. 31-1897, Nov. 13 (Box 10)
  - Accounts receivable, 1890-1903 (Box 11 (Oversize))